# Amit Khivesara

# Khivi



# Summary

Technical leader with 20 years of experience of leading enginering and data science teams to build business focussed solutions. I have been instrumental in transforming teams to the next stage of their maturity. Over the years I have build strong technical discipline within organizations. Based on my experience as a technical leader I authored a book on company culture.

# Philosophy

Embrace Change	Change is inevitable	Be Lazy	Do more with less
Open Intent	Share before, not after	Roughly Right	Perfection is a myth
Be Inquisitive	Listen, Learn, Contribute	Feedback	Improve deployments
Outsource	Make oneself redundant	Measure Failure	Success travels easily

# Management Skills

Communications	Open	Productivity	Extreme Programming
Mentor	Individuals	Process	Continuous Learning
Manage	Global Teams	Technical	Excellence

# — Computer Skills

Recent	Scala, Shell, C/C++	Past	Python, Java, Kernel
Dabble	Golang, JavaScript	Systems	Databases, Networking
Passable	Perl. PHP. Ruby	Platforms	Linux, OpenStack, Kubernetes

### Experience

#### 2019–Present Senior Director, AI Engineering, Target.

Leading the AI team for supply-chain and forecasting

- ${\color{blue} \circ}$  Leading global team responsible for AI strategies for Supply Chain & Demand Forecasting
- o Transformed research culture to business focussed

#### 2017–2019 Director, Data Engineering, Target.

Leading the data science team for e-commerce search

- Managed the engineering and data-science team for e-commerce search
- o Integrated a AI deep learning model into production
- o Built a continous delivery culture

2019–Present **Technical Advisor**, *iDataGenie*. 2016–Present **Technical Advisor**, *Verne Global*.

#### 2016-Present **Technical Advisor**, Netcore.

#### 2016–2017 **Head of Engineering**, Emissary.io, New York City, NY.

Emissary is a platform connecting sales professionals with former executives who have specific knowledge about their important sales targets.

- Transformed processes to an agile development methodology
- Hardened security practises
- O Developed a testing culture

#### 2014–2016 Head of Engineering, Betterpath, New York City, NY.

Betterpath is a data driven health care startup focused on improving care for patients. I lead the engineering team.

- o Built and managed the engineering team
- o Setup outsourced QA team in Ukraine
- Obesigned and built reliable infrastructure

#### 2012–2013 Senior Software Engineer, Konnect2, Madison, NJ.

Konnect2 is a financial services firm specializing in providing structured data exchange and algorithms for the global bond market. As one of the company's first employees, I took the product from an idea to deployment.

- Built feed handlers for bond trading market streams
- Scaled infrastructure
- Designed and implemented deployment pipelines

#### 2008–2012 CTO, Mesh Capital, Jersey City, NJ.

Mesh Capital is a quantitative trading firm specializing in high-frequency trading. As the company's first employee I wrote the initial software that traded propriety capital

- o Built and managed the high-caliber engineering team
- o Primary responsible for Canada cash equities market
- Responsible to execution and delivery of strategic initiatives

#### 2005–2008 **Technical Lead**, Roundbox, Florham Park, NJ.

Roundbox developed infrastructure to support mobile broadcast environments. I lead the global engineering team responsible for our server offerings.

- o Leading a distributed global team
- Build the world's only solution to support multiple broadcast standards (US and Europe).
- o Contributor to industry standards to interoperate with large vendors

#### 2002–2005 Senior Software Engineering, Xebeo Communications, Iselin, NJ.

Xebeo was a successful company that built a high-speed carrier-grade MPLS router. UTStarcom bought Xebeo in May, 2003. I was leader within the software team and build and managed the network platform.

- o Primary engineering lead on platform
- o Architected the configuration and system datastore
- Responsible for the test automation framework

# 1996–2002 **Member of Technical Staff**, Bell Labs, Lucent Technologies, Murray Hill, NJ. DataBlitz is a high-performance, ACID, main-memory database system. I lead the team from a research prototype to worldwide deployment by Lucent within its flagship telecommunication products.

- o Deliver solutions with 5 nines reliability
- o Built database system 10 times read performance than any commercial database
- o Lead the team during organisation change to continue to deliver to customer

#### Education

- 1994–1996 MTech, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India.

  Masters in Computer Science and Engineering
- 1990–1994 **BTech**, *Indian Institute of Technology*, Bombay, India. Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering

#### Awards and Achievements

- 1999 **Awarded**, *Bell Labs*, Murray Hill, NJ. Bell Labs President's Silver Award
- 1994 Academic Distinction, GATE, 1994. All India Rank 9
- 1990 Academic Distinction, IIT JEE, 1990.

All India Rank 28

#### Publications

2015 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Companies.

Book available at http://a.co/iluqz2A

2020 Culture Seeds: Process, People and Software.

To be published

#### Interests

Privacy Technology and Society Music The Doors
Travel Small town America Enjoy Bourbon
Film Documentaries Food Korean